andrewsullivan.com 2011-12-31

# Privacy Policy - The Daily Beast

Privacy Policy

(effective as of September 8, 2011)

The Newsweek/Daily Beast Company LLC has prepared this privacy policy to help you understand more about how we collect, use, and disclose information that we collect about consumers through our web and mobile services, which we refer to here as the “Services,” and in connection with subscriptions to the print edition of NEWSWEEK Magazine. 

This policy does not cover information that we collect about you outside of our normal consumer services. For example, it does not cover information that we collect in news reporting or as a part of our business arrangements. Also, this policy does not cover information that you voluntarily make public, such as by posting it in a publicly accessible place on the Internet.

**What information do you collect about me?**

The information that we collect about you generally falls into three categories:

  * **Information that you provide.** We may collect information that you choose to provide to us (including in comments or other user content that you submit to us or when you subscribe to NEWSWEEK Magazine). This may include information such as your name, e-mail address, year of birth, gender, zip code, country, mailing address, and credit card number or other billing information. We may ask you for information when you register or subscribe, or at other times — such as when you enter a contest or participate in a promotion, when you provide content, or when you order products from us. 

  * **Automated information.** Using technologies that are widely used on the Internet, we also may automatically collect information about your computer or mobile device and online activity when you access the Services. For example, when you visit thedailybeast.com, we may collect your IP address, as well as information about which pages you visit and the page, if any, that referred you to our site. Similarly, when you use our mobile application, we may collect information about your mobile device, such as the type of mobile device you use or your device identifier.   

  * Location information. When you use the Services, we may collect information about your location separately from your address or other information that you provide to us explicitly.&nbsp; For instance, we may use the GPS feature of your mobile device or your IP address to help determine your geographic location.

If you prefer that we not know your geographic location, you can disable the function when you first use the service in which we collect information about your location (or later, if your mobile device allows you to change the settings after initial download). Disabling the geolocation function may prevent you from using certain features of our services that require location information.

We may combine the information that we collect with information that we obtain from other sources, such as our owners, including IAC, our past and present affiliates, including other IAC companies, and our business partners and service providers, and through our subscription process. For example, we may ask a service provider to supply us with demographic information or updated contact information for you. Also, we may receive information from the U.S. Postal Service to help us update the address on your print subscription if you move.

**How do you use this information?**

We use the information that we collect about you for these purposes:

  * for editorial purposes, such as in connection with our news reporting
  * to contact you to provide information about NEWSWEEK Magazine, The Daily Beast, or other products or services in which we believe you may be interested, including legal notices or information about changes to this policy or our Terms of Use
  * to manage your account, perform billing and payment activities, and update you on your account status (including confirmation of registrations or notices of subscription expiration)
  * to provide you with the products and services you request
  * to respond to your requests, questions, and comments
  * to perform business analyses or for other purposes to improve the quality of our business, the products and services we offer, including through surveys and questionnaires
  * to deliver targeted advertising, as described below
  * as we believe is necessary to protect our rights and the rights of others, including by enforcing our User Agreement
  * as otherwise described to you at the point of collection or pursuant to your consent

We also do research on our users’ demographics, interests, and behavior to help us publish NEWSWEEK Magazine and operate our services, for other business purposes, and in connection with our display of advertising (which we describe below). This research is based on the information you provide to us including upon registration, on order forms, during a promotion, in surveys, and on your use of our services.

**With whom do you share this information?**

_We may share the information that we collect about you through the Services in these ways:_

  * with authorized service providers that help us provide the Services or perform other business functions for us, such as sending emails, hosting web services, or distributing NEWSWEEK Magazine (but these service providers are not permitted to use personally identifiable information that we provide for any purpose other than to provide service to us)
  * with our corporate affiliates, including the IAC family of businesses
  * in the context of contests or other promotions in which we identify an outside entity, with the identified entity
  * with select third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes, although you may choose up front and at no cost that we not share personally identifiable information that we have collected about you for these purposes by emailing us at help [at] newsweekdailybeast.com
  * to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process, in response to a request for cooperation from law enforcement or another government agency, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims
  * when we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, or as otherwise required by law
  * to enforce our User Agreement and other agreements, or otherwise protect or defend our rights or property or the rights or property of others, or the safety of the public
  * in connection with a corporate transaction, such as a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale
  * in aggregated or other non-personally identifiable form
  * as otherwise described to you at the point of collection or pursuant to your consent

In addition, if you choose to participate in social features on the Services, such as commenting on a story or chatting with other users, any information that you submit will become public. It may become accessible through search engines or, if you sign in using credentials from a third-party social networking service, to users on that service. Unless otherwise noted, we do not limit the distribution of information that you share using these features.

**How do you decide which advertisements to show me on the Services?**

Many of the Services are offered to you free of charge, and we cover the cost of providing those services by displaying advertisements. Many of these advertisements are targeted, which means that advertisers tell us the type of audience they want to reach (for example, men over 25 years old). We will display the advertisement to users meeting those criteria, but we never provide the advertiser with information about the specific individuals who receive the ads. The targeted ads on the Services may be provided by us, or they may be provided by a third-party vendor. You can learn more about targeted ads, including how to opt out of receiving them, below.

**Does this privacy policy apply to information collected through third-party offerings?**

We sometimes partner with third parties that operate platforms that you can use to access our content. For example, you can sign up for a subscription to Newsweek on your Amazon Kindle or access The Daily Beast on your Apple iPad or iPhone.

Similarly, we may include in some of our Services features that integrate with third-party social networking services. To do this, we include in our web pages and apps code from the social networking service provider. This code may allow the service provider to collect information about your activities on the Services. If you are logged into the social networking service at the time, the service provider may also be able to identify you in connection with that information.

Although this privacy policy will apply to our use of information collected about you through these co-branded offerings, we do not control the privacy practices of our third-party partners. As a result, we want you to be aware that when you use these offerings you may be providing information to both us and our partner, and you should review the partner’s privacy policy to be sure that you know how it will use any data that it collects.

**How do you protect the security of the information you store?**

We have in place physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to protect the information we collect through the Services and in connection with NEWSWEEK Magazine subscriptions. However, no security system is impenetrable. We cannot guarantee the security of our database, nor can we guarantee that the information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us via the Services.

**Do you collect information from children?**

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have collected any personal information from a child under the age of 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information from our database promptly.

**What are cookies and how are they used on the Services?**

We may use cookies and other technologies to store information on your computer or mobile device. We use this information for a variety of purposes, such as to remember you when you return to our websites or to identify your activities as you use certain Services. To do this, we may store a unique identifier on your computer or device. As described above, advertising service vendors that serve ads into our site may also use their own cookies or identifiers.

You may opt-out of the browser cookies delivered through the Services by changing the setting on your browser. Please be aware that this will disable all cookies delivered to your browser, not just the ones that we deliver, and that you may not be able to use all of the Services if you do not allow the placement of cookies. Also, opting out of browser cookies will not disable other technologies that we may use to collect information from you.

You also can opt out of receiving information stored in Adobe Local Shared Objects, which are commonly referred to as “Flash cookies.” You can find more information about Local Shared Objects and how to disable them on Adobe’s website at http://kb2.adobe.com/cps/526/52697ee8.html. As with browser cookies, disabling Local Shared Objects may interfere with the proper functioning of the Services.

**What choices do I have regarding your use of information about me?**

**Email messages.** If you do not wish to receive emailed promotional material from us, you can email us at help [at] newsweekdailybeast.com. Please note that, even if you opt out of receiving promotional emails from us, we may still contact you to provide you with non-commercial messages, such as billing or legal notices. Also, if you opt out, we may not provide to you non-promotional material, such as our emailed newsletters and other content.

**Targeted advertising.** If you would prefer not to receive advertisements through the Services that are targeted to your interests, you can inform our advertising vendor, Google, Inc., of your preference by clicking the “Opt out” button at http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html. You also can manage your advertising preferences at http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/.   

In some cases, we and advertisers on the Services work with other third-party vendors to help deliver advertisements targeted to your interests. These vendors include ad networks and analytics providers, and they use cookies or other technologies to collect information about your online activity (e.g., the sites and pages you have visited) in order to help advertisers deliver particular ads that they believe you would find most relevant. Many third-party vendors that perform these functions are members of the Network Advertising Initiative or the Digital Advertising Alliance, and you can opt out of those vendors’ delivery of targeted advertising to you by visiting http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp and http://www.aboutads.info/choices/. Some of our Services use technology for this purpose provided by Adobe. You can express your preferences regarding Adobe’s use of information about you here.

Please note that, because these opt-out tools will place a cookie on your computer to record your opt-out preference, any actions you take using these tools will apply only to the web browser that you use to take the action. Also, these tools may not work as expected if you set your browser to refuse cookies.

Sometimes, our advertisers will contract with a third-party service to host their ads. In this case, an ad-serving vendor contacts the advertisers’ hosting service to obtain a particular advertisement. Because we do not have a relationship with these third parties, we do not have a mechanism to allow visitors to opt out of tracking by these vendors.

**Sharing of information collected online.** If you would like to opt out of our sharing of personal information that we collect about you through the Services, you can make that request by emailing us at help [at] newsweekdailybeast.com, explaining your request, and providing your name and email address. Please understand that it may take us a reasonable amount of time to cancel your registration after we receive your request and that your cancellation will not apply to our uses of information about you prior to our receipt of the request. If you make a cancellation request, you should not access the Services again, since we may not be able to preserve your opt-out preferences if you continue to access the Services after we cancel your registration.

Sharing of information collected through print subscriptions. If you would like to opt out of our sharing of personal information that we collect about you in connection with your subscription to the print edition of NEWSWEEK Magazine, please go to www.nwsub.com to log in to your account, then select “update privacy preferences.”

**What happens when this privacy policy changes?**

We may update this privacy policy in the future. We will notify you about material changes to this policy by sending a notice to the e-mail address you provided to us or by placing a notice on our website.

**Who should I contact if I have questions about this privacy policy?**

If you have any questions or concerns about this privacy policy, you may contact us at: help [at] newsweekdailybeast.com.
